# YURI KOROBOCHKIN

PHD IN ENGINEERING
R&D Full Cycle Engineer, Algorithmist Developer

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ykorobochkin Phone: 053-352-7585

Location: Israel, Petah Tikva E-mail; korobotchkin@gmail.com



## PROFESSIONAL SCIENCE FIELDS

- Linear Algebra
- Analytic Geometry
- Math Analysis
- Differential Equations
- Mathematical Programming/ Optimisation
- Linear Programming
- Discrete Programming
- Complex Analysis
- Theory of Probability
- Mathematical Statistics
- Filtration Theory
- Theoretical Mechanics
- Wave Processes
- Radar Theory
- Navigation
- Electric Drive
- Aerodynamics
- Missile Guidance System/Homing

## **TECHNICAL STACK**

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Programming languages C, C++, Python
- Qt, C++ Builder, MSVS,
- Tools: Matlab, ArcGIS, QGIS
- DataBases: SQL
- Git, Github

## **SUMMARY**

An experienced full cycle R&D Engineer with 30 years of proven track record in researching, developing and managing complex technical systems in various domains. A dedicated and self-motivated individual with great learning and analytical skills in programming and mathematics, strong communication skills, and a can-do attitude.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **R&D FULL CYCLE ENGINEER**

#### **WEIZMANN INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE**

Domain: Astrophysics, Digital signals processing

Period: Jun 2023 to now

Development of GPU-accelerated applications for digital signal processing of radio telescopes based on the CUDA library **Achievements:** Reduced running time of the coherent dedispersion algorithm for pulsars' signal detection by 100 times, allowing real-time processing of a raw signal

### **ANDREYEV ACOUSTICS INSTITUTE**

Domain: Offshore Exploration in Gas and Oil Fields

Period: Jan 2022 to Aug 2022

Developing algorithms and applications for

- calibration of an acoustic underwater positioning system
- a positioning of underwater vehicles

**Achievements:** increased the accuracy of seismic sensors installation by 3 times

## NAVY RESEARCH INSTITUTE "SALUT"

**Domains:** Radar Systems Desing, Geopositioning, Inertial Systems, RadioElectronic System Design, Optimal Control, Kalman Filtration, Wave Propagation, and Ballistics.

Period: Nov 2019 to Feb 2022

Developing algorithms and applications for

- complex radio-electronic system based on a vessel board
- simulation and effectiveness evaluation of a complex radioelectronic system based on a vessel board
- controlling PMSM electrical drive system, installed on a swaying platform
- co-alignment of a set of measuring gadgets based on a vessel board

Achievements: increased tracking targets accuracy by 2 times



## **EDUCATION**

1985 - PhD in Engineering 1980 - MS in Applied Mathematics Lomonosov Moscow State University

## **LANGUAGES**

Russian - native English - B2, upper-intermidiate Hebrew - א, beginner

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **BAUMAN UNIVERSITY**

**Domains:** Radar Systems Desing, Geopositioning, Inertial Systems, RadioElectronic Systems Design, Optimal Control,

Kalman Filtration, Wave Propagation.

Period: Jun 2018 to Dec 2019

Developing algorithms and applications for the effectiveness evaluation of a complex vessel radar system

Achievements: Made it possible to extract radar measurements in the simultaneous presence of sea-surface multipath

and electronic attack

#### **HELICOPTERS AVIONICA**

Domains: Control System Design, Helicopter Design, Aerodynamics, Stable Theory

Period: Jun 2018 to Mar 2019

Developing algorithms and applications for

- autopilot of helicopters with coaxial propellers scheme
- helicopter training apparatus

#### **NAVY RESEARCH INSTITUTE "AMETIST"**

Domains: Radar Systems Desing, Geopositioning, Inertial Systems, RadioElectronic Systems Design, Optimal

Control, Kalman Filtration, Wave Propagation

Period: Aug 2014 to Jun 2018

Developing algorithms and applications for

- controlling a complex radio-electronic system based on a vessel board
- simulation and effectiveness evaluation of a complex radio-electronic system based on a vessel board
- radar measurement extraction in the presence of a sea-surface multipath

Achievements: Made it possible to extract radar measurements in the presence of a sea-surface multipath

## "HYDROPROEKT" - SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH INSTITUTE

**Domains:** Hydrology, Geodesy **Period:** Dec 2013 to Aug 2014

Developing hydrological DEM for the basins of some of North Caucasus rivers to calculate the dams flooding areas

according to the SRTM

## "ZEMPROEKT" - CADASTRAL VALUATION HOLDING

**Domains:** Agriculture

Period: Nov 2009 to Nov 2013

Development of the algorithm and application for governmental cadastral valuation of agricultural land

1991-2009

#### **CEO OF OWN BUSINESS**

**EXPREINCE IS NOT RELEVANT** 

1980-1991

#### **R&D ENGINEER**

MISSILE DEFENCE SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT IN VARIOUS SOVIET UNION MILITARY SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH INSTITUTES